Krishna Kumar

Associate Developer at SAP

kk3108063@gmail.com

Summary

Professional Experience:- Summer Undergraduate Research Fellow at ACBR, New Delhi Specialties: Excellent in 1) C++ 2) C 3) Microsoft Word 4) Power Point Presentation 5) Anatomy and Physiology Lab 6) Handling of Softwares 7) handling of Machines and Equipments Very Good in Wet Lab 8)C# 9)SQL 10)Ruby 11)Chefcookbooks 12)JavaScript

Experience

Associate Developer at SAP

July 2014 - Present (8 months)

Summer Trainee at National Institute of Mental Health And Neuro Sciences(NIMHANS)

May 2013 - June 2013 (2 months)

Hands on training in the Biomedical Engineering Section with an exposure to the equipments being used in the departments of Neuro Imaging and Intervention Radiology, Neurophysiology and Neurology, Biophysics, Speech Pathology, Psychopharmacology etc

Summer Trainee at Dr. B. R. Ambedkar Centre for Biomedical Research

June 2012 - July 2012 (2 months)

Project: DOCKING STUDIES ON human TOPO2-# Guide Name: Dr. Madhu Chopra Duration: 8 Weeks Environment: Discovery Studio Project Profile: Docking is an in silico approach of drug designing. Docking is a measure step in drug designing procedure. It helps out in reducing the number of possible drugs available before approaching for in vivo methods. I used Discovery Studio fr the same for Docking on human TOPO2-# which was done with four topoisomerase inhibitors namely Etoposide, Amsacrine, Teniposide and Voreloxin. Etoposide was taken as the reference and the study of the other three inhibitors were done against Etoposide. Interactions of Teniposide were very much similar to Etoposide whereas that of Voreloxin deviated a lot.

Projects

Development of a simultaneous temperature and humidity monitoring device.

January 2014 to Present

Members: Krishna Kumar, Ripunjay chachan, dablu ranjan kumar

Development of an ultrasonic cane as a navigation aid for the blind people

July 2013 to April 2014

Members: Krishna Kumar

Abstract: The current study deals with the development of an ultrasonic based cane for the navigation of the blind persons. The developed cane is able to detect both aerial and ground obstacles and potholes (dropoff). The ultrasonic signals are acquired in the Arduino microcontroller, classified and control signals are generated. The control signals are transmitted wirelessly to the receiving device, kept in the shoulder pocket. The receiving device consists of another Arduino microcontroller which triggers 3 speaker panel (worn around the chest) and 3 LED panel. The device works in the range of 5-150 cm and may be used as a navigational aid for the blind persons.

Skills & Expertise

C#

Microsoft Office

C

C++

.NET

Biomedical Engineering

Biophysics

Discovery Studio

Matlab

Drug Design

Docking

Image Processing

Programming

Signal Processing

PowerPoint

Microsoft Excel

Data Structures

MySQL

Java

HTML

Microsoft Word

SQL

Windows

Education

National Institute of Technology Rourkela

B.tech, Bio Medical Engineering, 2010 - 2014

Grade: Graduated

Activities and Societies: Event Co-ordinator at Innovision Event Manager at Catapult Glider and Boomerang

Modelling Workshop

Interests

Fishing, Snake Wrangling, AOE-II, photography, Caricature.

Krishna Kumar

Associate Developer at SAP

kk3108063@gmail.com



Contact Krishna on LinkedIn